那个人不是我杀的  迈克尔
I didn't kill that man, Michael.
证据表明是你杀的
The evidence says you did.
-我是被陷害的  -向我发誓
- I was set up. - Swear to me.
我向你发誓  迈克尔
I swear to you, Michael.
m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
放下你的武器
Put down your weapon!
我认为  你必须遭受坐牢的刑罚
I find it incumbent that you see the inside of a prison cell,
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
斯科菲尔德先生
Mr. Scofield.
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     折千纸鹤的小熊    米帅家的薇薇安
我在找一个人  一个叫林肯·布鲁斯的人
I'm looking for someone-- guy named Lincoln Burrows.
你为什么这么迫切地想见到布鲁斯
Why you want to see Burrows so bad anyhow?
因为他是我哥
'Cause he's my brother.
翻译     普利星布里狗   姚老师越狱实验室
-我要带你离开这里  -那不可能
- I'm getting you out of here. - That's impossible.
如果这个地方是你设计的  就有可能
Not if you designed the place, it isn't.
翻译     ABC的母上大人爱看越狱
你还真能折腾  你知道吗
You one mixed-up cracker, you know that?
我们成交吗
Are we in business?
翻译     智性恋的玛格丽   冰卡在机场赶着翻译
现在  全看时机了
Now... it's all about timing.
斯科菲尔德  你就跟传说中一样帅气
Scofield. You just as pretty as advertised.
翻译     盐湖凉开水      妖精希亚
我们什么时候开始
When do we get started?
-我需要你的帮助  -你是要我触犯法律
- I need your help. - You're asking me to break the law.
我是请求你犯个错
I'm asking you to make a mistake.
校对     普利星布里狗
忘记锁门
Forget to lock up.
快点儿
Come on.
校对     不上课的匡老师就是要越狱
我们做到了  迈克
We did it, Mike.
校对     不高兴抱走米胖胖
不管结果如何
However this plays out...
我都不后悔
I have no regrets.
校对     何何的小口袋只给茶包哥来牵
迈克尔
Michael!
如果你们在看这个  说明你们安全了
Well, if you're watching this, that means you're safe.
校对     冰卡在机场赶着翻译
我希望我能和你们在一起
I wish I could be there with you,
但正如你们所知  我剩下的时间不多了
but as you know now, I wouldn't have had much time.
时间轴  风吹来的那片云
我做出了选择
I made my choice.
我不后悔
I don't regret it.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
现在我们自由了
We're free now.
后期     咖啡·Lee
丈夫  父亲  兄弟  叔叔  朋友
我们自由了
We're free.
欲变世界  先变其身
总监     何何的小口袋只给茶包哥来牵
自由是有代价的
Freedom has a price.
七年前我死了
I died seven years ago.
留下了一个哥哥
Left behind a brother...
一个妻子
a wife...
一个儿子
a son.
但是死人会说话
But the dead talk...
如果你在倾听
if you listen.
他们就和你在一起
They're there with you...
发出联系
reaching out...
试着告诉你一些事
trying to tell you something.
因为并不是所有的死亡都一样
Because not all deaths are the same.
有些是真的
Some are real.
有些是一个故事
Some are a story.
问题是
Question is...
你相信故事吗
do you believe the story?
那个死去的人
Was the man who died
是你曾了解一个人
who you thought he was?
死人会说话
The dead talk...
如果你在倾听的话
if you listen.
伊利诺斯州  福克斯河监狱  当下
依旧是
Still tight as...
宝刀未老啊
scales on a snake.
上头肯定有人吧  拜格威尔
Must have friends in high places, Bagwell.
一个像你这样的臭粪池怎么会出狱
How a cesspool like you gets his walking papers
我永远不会知道
I'll never know.
这个臭粪池一直是个模范公民
This cesspool has been a model citizen.
模范公民哟
Model citizen.
71.31块
$71.31.
笔记本电脑
Laptop.
一包口香糖  还有三片
Pack of gum, three pieces.
要不你留着那个吧
How about you keep that?
不管你带进来什么  你都带出去
Whatever you bring in, you bring out.
还有最后的一封信
And one last piece of correspondence.
我一周收到几封信是给你这样的人
Something really wrong with the world when I'm receiving
这个世界一定是出了什么问题
dozens of letters a week for guys like you.
没什么能跟电子邮件比的
Nothing compared to the e-mails.
你们这些凶手为什么总是
What is it with you killers that put the satin
喜欢糟蹋好东西呢
on women's panties anyhow?
监狱
悲哉
Lackaday!
芝加哥
布鲁斯
Burrows!
你走出来怎么样
How about you step out
把欠的十万还给我们
and pay us the hundred grand you owe us?
不说话就当你是拒绝
Take that as a no.
林肯·布鲁斯
Lincoln Burrows...
拒绝了
says no.
彪悍的大块头
Big tough guy...
从贫民区出人头地
who made it out of the neighborhood.
看看你现在  落叶归根
And look at you now-- back to your roots,
回到你一贯的样子
the way you've always been.
还不起债的小毛贼
A small-time crook who can't pay his debts.
我们会找到你的
We're gonna find you, you know,
然后把你开膛破肚
and we're gonna open you up.
林小肯肯
Lincolny-linc.
上气不接下气
All huffin' and puffin'.
别用那种鄙夷的眼神来看我
Don't you look at me like I'm trash.
我的麻烦都解决了  我已经和政府
My house is in order. I'm clear with the government,
狱政局  还有我的上帝都两清了
the D.O.C. and my God.
然而看起来你却不同
Doesn't appear to be the same with you.
看看你  又堕落了
Look at you, all backslid.
你本应该随着年纪增长步步提升的
You're supposed to be going up in the world as you age,
还是你没听说过吗
or did you not get the memo?
你再不滚出我的门口  我就让你开瓢
You don't get off my deck, I'm gonna crack your skull.
换做我就不会这么做
I wouldn't do that.
命运似乎又赐予我们
Seems fate has deigned
密不可分的机会
to join us at the hip once again,
尽管我们相看两厌
despite our mutual contempt.
瞧瞧这个
Have a look-see.
你从哪得到的这个
Where'd you get this?
这周早些时候出狱时收到的
Received it on release earlier this week.
没有回信地址
No return address.
如果你在耍我  我宰了你
If you're playing me, I'll kill you.
看看那上面的邮戳
Take a look at that postmark on that.
我可能是个高手
I may be a sophisti-cat,
但也没有高到
but not so sophisticated
能伪造出这种东西的程度
as to forge something like that.
更何况
Besides...
我能安着什么心来你这里
what angle could I possibly have in coming here
跟你说  看起来你弟弟
and telling you that it looks like your brother
似乎还活着
might just be alive?
越狱
第五季第一集
这不可能
It's impossible.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
他怎么会寄给你
Why'd he send it to you?
再说一遍  我也是这么想的
Again, what I thought.
致西尔多·拜格威尔
福克斯河监狱
之后我又重新看了遍这段话
And then I gave the words another look-see.
兴许这就是答案
Maybe that's the answer.
"经汝之手
"By your hand
晓后世之荣耀
"You shall know the glories of your Progeny
吾等世界将拨乱反正  永垂不朽"
"And our world will be made right forevermore."
我他妈怎么知道这什么意思
Hell if I know what that means.
但正如这个信封是寄给我的
But just like that envelope's addressed to me,
这段话也是给我的  一定是的
those words are addressed to me. Got to be!
滚
‭Get out.
我是在帮你理清思路
I'm trying to work with you here.
有没有任何可能你弟弟活下来了
Is there any possible way your brother could've survived?
我弟弟已经死了
My brother's dead.
那又是谁寄的这个  为什么呢
Th-Then who sent this? And why?
快滚
Get out.
至少让我带走我合法的信件
Least let me take my rightful correspondence.
我做了备份  布鲁斯
Oh, I made a copy, Burrows.
虽然我早知道你还是一如既往的顽固不化
I knew you'd be the same obstinate son of a beyotch you always been,
但是我还是曾指望过你能开窍
but I'd hoped you'd seen the light.
然而你依然是狗改不了吃屎
But you are what you is and you is what you are.
但我还是要告诉你
Still, I'm telling you...
命运不知为何又让我们密不可分
fate has got us joined at the hip somehow.
纽约州  雪城
你从哪儿来的
Where you in from?
芝加哥
Chicago.
超爱芝加哥
Love Chicago.
-给你  -谢谢  哥们
- There you go. - Thanks, man.
纽约州  伊萨卡
我以为再也不会见到你
I didn't think I was ever gonna see you again.
你没来参加婚礼
You didn't come to the wedding.
我心想...  我懂
I mean, I figured I...I get it--
你恨我嫁给了你弟弟以外的人  但...
he hates me for marrying someone other than his brother, but...
我一直过得不太好  莎拉
I haven't been in a good place, Sara.
我的脑子一直以来一片混乱
My brain, it's... it's been a mess.
所以我才没来
That's why I didn't show up.
我不想让我的侄子看到我那副鬼样子
And... I didn't want my nephew to see me like that.
不过现在想置身事外都不可能了
But now it's impossible to stay away.
居然有人连这都要开玩笑
Someone's got a sick sense of humor.
我明白你希望这是真的
I know you want it to be true.
失去兄弟
Losing a brother--
仿佛生活中出现一个巨大的空洞
the massive hole that leaves in your life.
失去丈夫也一样
Like the same massive hole losing a husband is.
也许吧
Maybe.
林肯·布鲁斯
Lincoln Burrows?
雅各布
Jacob.
好久不见
I haven't seen you in what,
-都有三四年了吧  -是啊
- three, four years?  - Yeah.
林肯叔叔
Uncle Lincoln!
小子
Buddy!
见到你真好
So good to see you.
你有给我带捞出来的宝贝吗
Did you bring me any sunken treasures?
捞出来的宝贝
Sunken treasures?
潜水用具店
The dive shop.
-在巴拿马  -没错  我经常跟他讲
- Panama. - ‭Yeah, I've been telling him stories
在我们还没回到这之前  在那儿经历的事情
about being down there before we came back to the States.
你对于他而言
You've become kind of like
已经是神话般的英雄了  我去拿点啤酒
a mythological hero to him. Let me get some beers.
-我们聊聊你的近况  -好啊
- I want to know what you been up to. - Sure, man. Yeah.
好
Okay.
过来
Come here.
先去清洗下  好吗
I want you to go wash up, okay?
然后就能和叔叔好好叙旧了
And then you can catch up with your uncle.
他不仅把你当神话  迈克尔在他心里也一样
He hasn't just mythologized you. He mythologizes Michael, too.
仿佛觉得他生来便是神一样的存在
It's like someone thinking he was born to a god,
一个他从未见过的神...
a god he's never met...
一个不仅是现在
and who isn't here.
以后也永远不会出现的神
And who never will be again.
我得面对现实
I can be pragmatic.
当初迈克尔病了
Michael was sick.
得了绝症
He was terminally sick,
他死了
and he died.
莎拉
Sara...
那你要怎么解释这个
how do you explain that?
这不是原始照片  林肯
It's Photoshop, Linc,
它被处理过了
or something.
你得想想这是谁给你的
You got to consider the source.
这毕竟是来自茶包哥啊
This came from T-Bag.
我知道你希望这是真的
I know you want it to be true.
我又何尝不是
I want it to be true.
精品酒店
今晚来个约会如何  模范市民
How about a date tonight, model citizen?
长期漂泊过后
A little well-earned love
应当来点爱的滋润
after a long time at sea.
桃乐茜小姐
Miss Dorothy.
来自伊利诺斯州的奥罗拉
E-mailing her undying love
为她送去永恒之爱的问候
from Aurora, Illinois.
哎呦我去
I-eesh.
这个怎么样
How about this one?
"爱你的坎农·阿隆佐  于尚佩恩城"
"Love Cannon Alonzo in Champaign."
光对着这名字就能撸一发
Hop on that just on the name alone.
明日预约
义肢研究中心主任  惠特库姆医生
德兰大学101大楼  晚上9点30分
什么鬼
What the hell?
义肢研究
Prosthetic research?
你的莎拉很聪明
Smart girl, your Sara.
她说得对
She's right.
迈克尔·J·斯科菲尔德
1974年8月10日-2010年4月11日
丈夫  父亲  兄弟  叔叔  朋友
欲变世界  先变其身
我只是太想念你了
I'm just desperate to see your face.
自从你走了  我的生活变得一团糟
My life's been a mess ever since you left.
我又重操旧业了
Fallen back into my old ways.
一些你看不惯的事情
Something you wouldn't tolerate.
但我心深处  良善犹在  迈克尔
But I got good in me, Michael.
良善犹在
I got good in me.
要是你能回到我身边
It'd just be nice if
帮我找回失落的心  那该多好啊
you were here to... help me find it.
迈克尔·J·斯科菲尔德
1974年8月10日-2010年4月11日
丈夫  父亲  兄弟  叔叔  朋友
欲变世界  先变其身
所以...
So... yeah.
经汝之手  晓后世之荣耀
吾等世界终将拨乱反正  永垂不朽
"奥杰吉亚"
"Ogygia."
也门  萨那  奥杰吉亚监狱
告诉我你在哪
Telling me where you are.
奥杰吉亚监狱
只有一种方法能查出真相了
There's only one way to find out.
惠特库姆医生
义肢主任
西尔多·拜格威尔
Theodore Bagwell.
您就是邀请我
And you're Dr. Whitcombe,
在整栋楼的其他部分都关门的时候
the man who invited me to this mystery meeting
来参加九点半神秘会议的惠特库姆医生
at 9:30 at night when the rest of the building's closed.
我知道你做过什么
I know what you've done.
所以我不想被人看到我跟你这种人在一起
That's why I don't want to be seen associating with your sort.
我只想知道我为什么来这里  以及
Just want to know why I'm here, and...
这事跟我在监狱里收到的特殊信封
if this has anything to do with that special envelope
有没有任何关系
I received in the prison.
我对信封的事情一无所知
I know nothing about an envelope.
我只能告诉你我的工作
I can only tell you my work.
目标肌肉神经移植术
Targeted muscle reinnervation.
通过大脑操控义肢
Using the brain to manipulate prosthesis
就像你天生的肢体一样
as it were a natural limb.
但是同其他前沿技术一样
But as with any cutting-edge work,
资金并不容易筹备  然而
funding is not easy to find, and yet,
意外的是  我收到了赠款
incredibly, I got the grant
而且一笔数量可观的匿名捐款
in the form of a considerable anonymous grant
只有一个条件
on one condition--
我的第一个义肢接受者
the first recipient of my procedure...
必须是你
is you.
我可以给你配备
I can equip you
一个行动自如的义肢
with a fully articulate prosthetic,
在使用上与真手毫无差异
operationally indistinguishable from a real hand.
这都是因为一位匿名捐助者
All of this because of an anonymous donor?
看来有人是给咱俩都策划好了
Someone seems to have plans for both of us.
如果你感兴趣的话
I've reserved an operational lab for Monday
我已经预订了周一的实验室
if you decide you are interested.
毕竟这是你的手
It's your hand, ultimately.
经汝之手
By your hand,
晓后世之荣耀
you shall know glories of your progeny.
你说什么
What's that?
没什么  医生
Nothing, Doc.
快啊  迈克尔
Come on, Michael.
你肯定给我留下了什么线索
You must have left me something.
快啊
Come on!
快
Come on.
什么情况
What's going on?
天啊  发生了什么
Oh, my God, what happened?
我不清楚  我去报警
I'm not sure. I'm gonna call the police.
喂
Hello?
我把迈克尔的坟墓挖开了  他不在里面
I dug up Michael's grave. He's not in it.
他...什么
He... What?
莎拉  刚才有人想杀我
Sara, someone just tried to kill me.
他们一直在盯着我  他们一直在盯着我
They've been watching. They've been watching,
-可能就是为了...  -谁想要杀你
- probably for... - Who tried to kill you?
从机场就有人在跟踪我  我...
It started at the airport. I...
有一辆红色小轿车
There was a... a red sedan.
一直跟着我
It started following me.
然后他们...他们换了一辆
Then they... they... they swapped down to a...
什么来着  换了一辆小货车
What was it? A pickup.
那辆小货车是什么颜色的
What color was the pickup?
黑色的
Black.
怎么了
Why?
莎拉
Sara?
雅各布
Jacob?
-什么事  -那面砖墙上有一幅画后面
- Yeah. ‭- Behind one of the pictures on the brick wall,
有个洞  里面有把枪
there's a hole, and there's a gun in it.
-我需要你把它拿出来  -什么
- I need you to get it. - ‭What?!
快点  快点  有人找到我们头上了
Right now! Right now! Someone's coming for us!
一把枪  一把枪是什么意思
A gun? What do you mean, a gun?
麦克
Mike?
911  您遇到什么紧急情况
9-1-1. What is your emergency?
我家有人持械入室
I have an armed intruder in the house.
我需要你们马上派人来
I need you to send people right away.
我没有时间了  求你们快点来
I don't have time. Please, come.
-麦克  -莎拉
- Mike? - Sara?
发生什么事了  萨拉
What's going on, Sara?
-妈妈  -过来
- Mom? - ‭Come here.
莎拉  莎拉
Sara? Sara!
就我一个人  家里没有别人
It's just me. There's no one else in the house.
-你想干什么  -快进浴缸
- What do you want? - Get in the tub.
外面是谁  妈妈  他们想干什么
Who's here, Mom? What do they want?
我也不知道  宝贝
I don't know, baby.
好的  听我说  无论谁进了门
Okay, listen to me, if anyone comes through that door,
千万不要动  好吗
you don't move, okay?
我会用这个捅他们  你不会受到伤害的
I will put this through them, and you will not be harmed.
听懂了吗  好孩子
You understand? Good boy.
雅各布
Jacob?
妈妈
Mom.
把你能找到的毛巾都拿来
Go get every towel you can find.
快去  快去
Right now, right now.
拜托  雅各布
Please, Jacob.
好吧  我觉得伤到动脉了  坚持住
Okay. I think it got an artery. Stay with me.
我要你看着我  好吗
I want you to look at me, all right?
别闭眼睛  别睡
Don't close your eyes and don't go to sleep,
好吗  我要你保持清醒
all right? I'm gonna need you to stay with me.
快叫救护车
I need an ambulance!
他怎么样了
How is he?
子弹几乎贯穿他的股动脉
The shot almost completely severed his femoral artery
他们正在努力让他的情况稳定下来
so they're trying to stabilize him.
他呢
And him?
他才七岁
He's seven.
怎么样  小麦
How you doing, Mikey?
出事了  对吗
Something's happening, isn't it?
先是你来了
First, you come
然后那个人进了我们家
and that person came in our house.
是关于我亲生父亲的事  对吗
It has something to do with my real father, doesn't it?
为什么那样说
Why do you say that?
因为我能从她的脸上看出来
Because I can see it in her face.
我去和你叔叔说几句
I'm gonna need to talk to your uncle.
我就在那边
I'm gonna be right over there
你能看到的地方  行吗
where you can see me. Okay?
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我们唤起了一些事
We've awoken something.
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
Something people are trying to hide about Michael.
你弟弟死了  林肯
Your brother's dead, Lincoln.
要是他死了  那尸体呢
Or is he dead? Where is the body?
那为什么他要离开
Then why did he leave?
如果这些年他还活着
If he's been out there for all of these years,
他为什么要抛弃他自己的儿子
why did he abandon his own son?
你知道我是对的
You know I'm right.
如果没事  情况不会像现在这样
It wouldn't be like this if something wasn't happening.
-是不会  但...  -我们要反击
- It wouldn't, but... - Let's fight back.
我都不知道我们在反击谁
I don't know who we're fighting.
我们去也门查清楚
Let's go to Yemen and find out.
去也门  我还有个儿子  林肯
To Yemen? I have a son, Lincoln.
我丈夫还在急诊室
My husband's in the ER. Right?
听着  此刻离开他们
Look, leaving them is exactly the wrong thing
是我最不应该做的事
for me to do right now.
夫人  他可以见你了
Ma'am. He's ready to see you.
马上来
One second.
我会去
I'll do it.
我会去也门
I'll go to Yemen.
你对也门一无所知
You don't know a damn thing about Yemen.
我会找到有门路的人
I'll find someone who does.
回见了  小麦
See ya, Mikey.
纽约州  布法罗
我羡慕你
I envy you.
你扭转了你的命运
You changed your life around.
一个厌倦了放荡不羁的人
A man gets tired of living a profligate life.
所以我参加了圣战
So I took up jihad.
真正的圣战  不是新闻上看到的一片疯狂
Real jihad, not that madness that you see on the news.
内心的战争
War within.
为洗心革面而做的精神斗争
The spiritual struggle to clean up your act.
追寻并侍奉安拉
Finding and serving God.
那挺好的  伙计
That's good, man.
世界需要它  小林
The world needs it, Linc.
我是说  我们在这里是渺小的存在
I mean we're, uh, we're small here
但我们能竭尽所能
but we do what we can
帮助中东地区的维和工作
to help the peace efforts in the Middle East.
在本国组织反激进运动
Working on anti-radicalization campaigns here at home.
正如我说的  斗争
Like I said, the struggle.
那也就是我来的原因
That's why I'm here.
如果我要去也门
If I needed to get to Yemen,
你能帮上忙吗
that something you could help me with?
我以为他死了
I thought he was dead.
大家也是
So did everyone.
但是在奥杰吉亚
But Ogygia?
我的意思是  那里关的都是
I mean, that's for heavy hitters,
大人物和政治犯
political prisoners.
在也门  这是最糟糕的事了
In Yemen, it doesn't come any worse.
我是说  你知道伪造死亡有多复杂吗
I mean, do you know what it would take to stage a death?
更不用说让一个活人
Not to mention keeping a man who is not dead
在没人察觉的情况下生活七年
under the radar for seven years.
这些人来头不小啊
Some very powerful players.
赛义德  你了解这个清真寺吗
Sayed, what do you make of this mosque right here?
阿克萨清真寺  萨那城里比较大的一个
Aksa Mosque. It's one of the main ones in Sana'a.
它是独一无二的
It's very distinct.
从寺院
Sightlines seem pretty consistent
可以毫无遮挡地看到监狱
with what it would probably be from the prison to the mosque.
奥杰吉亚监狱
我个人认为  照片是真的
Now, you ask me, that photo's legit.
那么  我弟弟就在那里
Then that's the building my brother's in.
最简单的做法就是给监狱打电话问问
Easiest way to find out is to call the prison and ask.
我找迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Mafi Michael Scofield.
谢谢
Shukran.
没有叫迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的
There's no Michael Scofield.
在网上搜一张图片
Punch up an image from the Internet.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.
给监狱发过去
Send it to the prison.
可能他用了别的名字
Maybe he's under a different name.
听着  小林  我得说句话
Listen, Linc, I got to say something, man.
你不能这么着急
Man, you got to slow your roll.
也门正在打内战
Yemen is in a civil war.
整个国家就快崩溃了
They're really close to collapse.
如果一个拿美国护照的白人
It's no place for a white man with an American passport,
没有阿拉伯人的帮助  是不可能出现的
no command of Arabic, to just show up on a whim.
但是很显然  我弟弟做到了
And yet, apparently, my brother did.
找到一张照片  是你弟弟
Got a picture. Your brother's intake photo
在福克斯河监狱的入监照
from the Fox River Penitentiary.
这张是车管所的照片
Here's his DMV photo
还有张他以前工作单位网站的照片
and here's a photo from his old workplace Web site.
那不是他
It's not him.
都不是
None of them are.
有人要把他从历史上抹去
Someone's erasing him from history.
林肯  你要去哪儿
Lincoln, where are you going?
回酒店收拾  然后去机场
Hotel, to grab my stuff, then the airport.
听我说  你不要去也门
Hey, listen. You're not going to Yemen.
-那就拦着我啊  -你撑不了三天
- Stop me. - ‭You won't make it three days.
我们得走正规渠道
We need to go through the proper channels.
正规渠道
The proper channels?
有人要让他彻底消失
Someone's erasing his existence.
谁干的  谁有这个能力
Who does that? Who has that ability?
我跟你说  迈克尔可能
I'm telling you, Michael's caught
被卷入到什么严重的事情里了
in the middle of something big.
如果不是呢
What if he's not caught in the middle?
你什么意思
What are you saying?
迈克尔不会向别人低头
Michael has never been anyone's sucker.
他总是可以控制大局  从来都是
He's always been in control. Always.
你是说他伪造了自己的死
You saying he faked his own death?
我是说在你进入战区前
I'm saying you need to look at all of the possibilities
要考虑到所有可能性
before you walk into a war zone.
我不确定你会来
I wasn't sure you'd come.
有时候人得向命运屈服
Sometimes a man has to surrender to fate.
看看命运为他准备了什么
See what it has in store for him.
我们得给你麻醉
We'll need to put you under.
不  不  不  我不做全身麻醉  同志
No, no, no. I don't do general anesthetic, compadre.
这样的手术必须做全麻
It's mandatory for a procedure like this.
请原谅我
You'll forgive me
我不喜欢没有知觉的时候
if I have a problem lying unconscious
有人用利器对着我
before a man with sharp items at his disposal.
不全麻这手术没法做
It cannot be done without a general anesthetic.
我以前做过  朋友
I've done it before, friend.
上次的手术可不成功啊
And look what it got you.
你要是在我昏迷时让我出什么意外我就会...
You do anything untoward to me while I'm under and I'll...
我最不想招惹的人就是你了
You are the last man I'd run afoul of.
明白吗
Okay?
命运啊  你这个神秘的小婊子
Oh fate, you mysterious bitch.
为什么要这样对我
Why you doing this to me?
干洗好了  外套不错
Dry cleaning. Nice jacket.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
祝你今天开心
Have a good day.
你这是干什么
What the hell was that for?
苏克雷  你怎么来了
Sucre, what the hell are you doing here?
钞票哥都告诉我了
C-Note told me what's going on.
他叫你来说服我吗
He tell you to talk me out of it?
不  我要跟你一起去
No. I'm coming with you.
你不能去
You're not coming.
迈克尔是我最好的朋友
Michael's my best friend.
如果他还活着  如果他有麻烦  我想帮忙
If he's alive, if he's in trouble, I want to help.
你就没有个工作吗
Don't you have a job or something?
有啊  跑码头  虽然活不是很好
Yeah, on a tramp. Not great work,
Tramp  也有妓女或流浪汉之意
但是  我可是有前科的  对吧
but hey, I'm an ex-con, right?
跑码头吗
Tramp?
是啊  我"干"了有一阵子了
Yeah, I've been riding her for a while.
你是干什么的  皮条客吗
What are you, a pimp?
什么  不  不是
What? No. No, no, no.
跑码头是自由货船的意思
A tramp is a freelance cargo ship.
我们去过香港  西班牙  布宜诺斯艾利斯
We go to Hong Kong, Spain, Buenos Aires,
基本上老板让我们去哪就去哪
basically wherever the boss tells us.
败家子一个
Corrupt son of a bitch.
那我建议你继续做你的事
Well, I suggest you get back on that tramp,
因为你不能去
'cause you're not coming. ‭
我告诉你  我能帮上忙
I'm telling you, I can help!
听我说  这可是中东
‭Listen to me, this is the Middle East.
我现在已经变了  全世界我都熟
Lots has changed. I'm an international hitter now.
我很健谈
A raconteur.
你这就词不达意了
I don't think that means what you think it means.
别说的像我不懂法语一样  我懂法语
Don't speak to me like I don't know French, I know French.
我是棕色人种  这点很重要
And I'm brown, that's something.
我在那边
I'll fit in better over there
会比你更合群
than you will, snowflake.
我之前说你三天内就得死
I decided I was wrong when I said
我觉得我错了
you would be dead inside of three days.
你去那边  一天就死了
You go over there, you'll be dead inside of one.
但是有我在就不同了  我们有人
But with me, we have people at the mosque
在那边的清真寺工作
that have worked over there,
我们有法律关系
people with legal connections
可以带我们进入监狱
that can get us inside of that prison.
等等  你没说他能跟着去
Hold on. You're not saying he gets to go.
他比我还不像棕色人种
He's not any browner than I am.
但你会说阿拉伯语吗
不会吧
No?
我在伊拉克当兵时
I managed to pick up a little Arabic
好不容易学了几句阿拉伯语
while I was serving in Iraq.
肯尼迪机场前往也门的39号航班
This is the final boarding call for Flight 39 to JFK,
这是最后一次登机广播
connecting to Yemen.
这是最后一次登机广播...
This is the final boarding...
听着  伙计
Listen, man.
我以后肯定会需要你的帮助
There's gonna be a time when I'm gonna need you.
你最好能找到他
You better find him.
找到他以后你一定打电话告诉我
And you better call me when you do.
我会的
I will.
你真的有人脉吗
You really got contacts?
是人脉网络
Contacts with contacts.
其实可以跟着他们去洗手间
Could just follow 'em into the bathroom,
控制住他  绑在柱子上  这事就解决了
ragdoll him in one of stalls and be done with it.
那我们还得处理尸体
Then we'd have a body to deal with.
我们要让他彻底地消失  不留后患
And we want him utterly and irrevocably gone from this world.
掘地三尺  也不会找到
Where no amount of digging will bring him back.
也门  萨那
入境的只有我们两个人
We're the only ones coming into the place.
是啊  这个国家已支离破碎了  大家都想逃出去
Yeah the country is falling apart. Everyone wants out.
联系人叫什么
Who is that contact again?
一个叫希巴的女人
A women named Sheba.
是个上线  她在这里给
A handler, she helps to track the Americans
前来支援的美国军队提供帮助
that come and help to fight the GI fight.
欢迎来到内战
Welcome to the civil war.
富兰克林先生
Mr. Franklin,
希巴女士让我来接你
Ms. Sheba sent me to collect you.
你好
As-salaam alaikum.
Wa alaikum as-salaam.
这边走  先生们  跟我来
This way, gentlemen. Follow me.
布鲁斯和富兰克林
也门很危险
Yemen very dangerous.
你从来都不知道谁是敌人  谁是朋友
You never know who's enemies, who's friends.
人人都会在对方背后捅刀
Everyone scratching each other's backs.
ISIL恐怖组织正开始袭击城市
ISIL is starting to attack the city.
伊拉克和黎凡特伊斯兰国
逊尼派穆斯林极端武装组织
他们几个月来一直在沙漠里进行活动
They have been building up out in the desert for months.
如果他们...攻下了这座城
If they... take the city,
就会杀了所有的世俗主义者
they will kill all the secularists,
执行伊斯兰教教法  你懂的
install Sharia law. You know.
你好像并不担心
You don't seem worried.
亲爱的朋友  我也会在背后捅人刀
I scratch backs, too, my friend.
不不不  这里不对
No, no, no, no. This isn't right.
等等  这地址不对啊
Wait a minute. This... this isn't the address.
我要买烟  不不  不行
I get cigarettes. No, no, you don't.
立刻把我们送去目的地
You take us straight to the address right now!
我去买点烟
I-I get cigarettes.
林肯  这是个陷阱
Linc, this is a setup.
拿好你的包
Grab your bag now.
愿真主保佑你们平安
我们不想惹麻烦
美国监狱送上问候  小婊子们
Greetings from the U.S. prison system, bitches.
怎么回事
What is it?
有人算计了我们
Someone set us up.
快来
Come quickly.
否则我们都得死
Or we'll all be dead!
走走走  她是我们的人
Go, go. She's one of us.
快  拿上你的包  快  快走
Come on, grab your bag. Come on, let's go!
你是怎么找到我们的
How did you find us?
机场的一个线人看见你上错了的士
A contact at the airport saw you get into the wrong taxi.
被我找到算你幸运
You're lucky I found you.
这里的人都很激进
This is very radicalized neighborhood.
他们什么手段都能使出来的
Whoever set you up couldn't have set you up in a worse way.
把你们的手机扔出去
Throw your phones out the window.
我不想让别人跟踪我们
I don't want anyone tracking us.
快扔
Do it!
希巴  这位是林肯
Sheba, this is Lincoln.
林肯  这位是希巴
Lincoln... Sheba.
拜格威尔先生  您的手术完成了
You've been made whole, Mr. Bagwell.
您可以自行离开了
You're free to go.
我不走  除非你告诉我你在我身体里放了什么
Not till you tell me what you've put in me.
你是不是感觉不太舒服
You feel an unease, do you?
我猜这是你自打出生以来就有的东西
I'd venture that's what's always been in you since birth.
你的灵魂  我只是把硬体放了进去
Your soul. I just put the hardware into you.
你才是驱动它的主体
You're the thing that runs it.
-谁在背后指使...  -没人
- Who's behind... - ?Nobody!
没有人在背后指使我
Nobody's behind this.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
我就收到了一个词  仅此而已
I got a single word. That's it.
我的捐助人只用了一个词来代表他们身份
Just... my benefactors ID'd themselves by a single word.
乌提斯
Outis.
我搜索了一下
I looked it up.
这词在希腊语里意思是"没有人"
It's Greek for "Nobody."
那就是你的捐助人  拜格威尔先生
That's who your benefactor is, Mr. Bagwell.
没有人
Nobody.
卡尼尔·乌提斯
好了
Okay.
这人是谁
Who's this?
奥玛在奥杰吉亚监狱有些关系
Omar has connections in Ogygia Prison.
他说可以安排一次探视
He says he can arrange a visit.
这意思是说迈克尔在那里吗
That mean Michael's in there?
很显然那里有个美国人
There's apparently an American in there
符合你弟弟的特征
matching your brother's description.
只是有个问题
There's just one thing.
安排这样的探视很难  非常难
Arranging such a visit is hard. Very difficult.
-需要付出一定的代价  -钱不是问题
- Comes at a price. - Money's not a problem.
不是钱的问题
Not money.
是你的护照
Your passport.
我的护照
My passport?
怎么  你想要拿来看看
What, did... you want to hold it?
不不  公平交易
No. Straight trade.
用探视换你的护照
Visit for your passport.
美国护照在这里等同黄金
U.S. Passport is like gold here.
做些修改  就是一张通往自由国度的机票
A few changes, and it can be a ticket to freedom.
别这么做  林肯
Don't do it, Linc.
我知道这并不合你心意  但是
I know it is not ideal, but...
合心意这种事  在现在的也门早已成为历史
ideals as of right now are history in Yemen.
你没有护照没办法出国
You cannot get out of the country without a passport.
别给他
Don't do it.
如果这是真主的旨意
Inshallah...
你很快会见到你的弟弟的
you will see your brother soon.
我告诉过自己  只要我们从监狱出去
I told myself I'd never step foot in another prison.
我就永不再踏足进另一座监狱
As long as we walk out of it.
奥杰吉亚监狱
也门  萨那
这里没有迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
There's no Michael Scofield.
这是为了要我的护照而设的骗局
It was a scam to get my passport.
奥玛是我最信任的手下之一
Omar is one of my most trusted operators.
听着  女士
Listen, lady.
信任似乎在这个国家一钱不值
Trust doesn't seem to mean a whole lot in this country.
等我一下  行吗
Give me a second, okay?
我会想个变通的办法
I'll figure out a way to work this thing out.
有张图片
An image.
对吧  他们发给你的那张
Right? The one that they sent to you?
-对  对  -你带了吗
- Oh, yeah, yeah. - Do you have it?
看
Look.
给
There.
卡尼尔·乌提斯
Kaniel Outis.
对  卡尼尔·乌提斯  他在这里吗
Yes, Kaniel Outis. Is he here?
他说  对  图片中的男人就在这里
He says, yes, the man in the picture is here
我们可以去探视他
and we can see him,
但仅仅是因为我们跟希巴有交情
but only 'cause we're dealing with Sheba.
你为什么说这个名字
Why did you say that name?
是因为我弟弟的外套
Because of my brother's jacket.
我还以为在这件事上  你是站在真主这边的
Thought you were on the right side of God on this.
希巴  不  希巴
Sheba. No, hey, hey. Sheba...
卡尼尔·乌提斯是个臭名昭著的恐怖分子
Kaniel Outis is a big-time terrorist.
他因为谋杀被抓来的
They got him in here for murder.
他和ISIL恐怖组织是一伙儿的
He's been working with ISIL
伊拉克和黎凡特伊斯兰国
逊尼派穆斯林极端武装组织
企图颠覆政府
trying to take down the government.
别这么说  钞票哥
Come on, C.
你知道那决不是迈克尔
You know that's not Michael.
无论他是何方神圣
Well, whoever he is...
我们都要见到他了
...we're about to meet him.
我爸爸是个怎样的人
What was my father like?
我亲生爸爸
My real father.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield...
就像一场风暴
...was like a storm.
带上照相机
Grab the camera.
我想证明他还活着
I want to prove he's alive.
他颜值爆表
He was beautiful
令人生畏
and frightening
神秘莫测
and mysterious.
他会从湛蓝的天空中
And he would show up in your life
现身在你的生命里
out of the clear blue sky
来无影  去无踪
and then he would disappear just as quickly.
但风暴还是会回来的
But storms, they can come back.
不是吗
Can't they?
问题是  如果回来了
Question is, if they come back,
那会是人面依旧呢
is it the same storm,
还是物是人非了呢
or has something changed?
迈克尔
Michael.
新纹身
New tats.
你说的新是什么意思
What do you mean, new?
我们会把你救出来的
We're gonna get you out of here.
我的名字不叫迈克尔
My name isn't Michael.
我也不知道你们是谁
And I don't know who you are.
抱歉
Sorry.
狱卒  带我回牢房
迈克尔
Michael.
迈克尔  跟我说话啊  迈克尔
Michael, talk to me. Michael...
迈克
Mike.
迈克  你在干什么  该死的
Mike! What are you doing, damn it?!